Guide to the Sears Catalog Collection, 1910-1994
The John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Sears Catalog collection 1910-1994
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Sears, Roebuck and Company
12.0 Linear Feet 60 Items
Department store chain founded in 1893 as a mail order business; one of the largest retailers in the United States.
Collection consists of seasonal catalogs and wish books spanning the years 1910-1994. Catalogs featured the full range of items sold by Sears, from clothing to appliances and toys, and served as a bridge between the company's walk-in department stored and direct marketing mail order business. Initially featured unbranded products before adopting a number of Sears' house brands and eventually featuring nationally branded products. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Sears Catalog Collection were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1999.
Historical Note
Founded 1893 by Richard Sears and Alva Roebuck as a mail order business. Sears opened its first department stores in 1925 and rose to become the largest retailer in the United States. Acquired by KMart in 2005.
Collection Overview
Collection consists of seasonal catalogs and wish books spanning the years 1910-1994. Catalogs featured the full range of items sold by Sears, from clothing to appliances and toys, and served as a bridge between the company's walk-in department stored and direct marketing mail order business. Initially featured unbranded products before adopting a number of Sears' house brands and eventually featuring nationally branded products.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Sears, Roebuck and Company
Advertising -- Brand name products
Advertising -- Clothing and dress
Advertising, direct mail
Advertising, direct mail -- United States
Commercial catalogs
Direct marketing
Mail-order business
Mail order catalogs
Trade catalogs
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center Collections:
Abercrombie & Fitch Quarterly Catalog Collection
Arlie R. Slabaugh Collection of Direct Mail Literature
Bates Worldwide, Inc. Records
John Stevenson Papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Account Files
J. Walter Thompson Company. Domestic Advertisements Collection
Wells Rich Greene Inc. Records
Wunderman Archives
Detailed Description of Collection
- Sears Catalogs, 1910-1994
  - Ca. 1910s Chicago (Box 1)
  - 1914 Chicago (Box 1)
  - 1915 Chicago #131 (Box 2)
  - 1920 (spring) Dallas (Box 2)
  - 1920-1 (fall & winter) Philadelphia (Box 3)
  - 1925-6 (fall & winter) Chicago (Box 3)
  - 1928-9 (fall & winter) Philadelphia (Box 4)
  - 1930 (spring & summer) Philadelphia #160 (Box 4)
  - 1933 (spring & summer) Chicago #168 (Box 5)
  - 1935-6 (fall & winter) Dallas #171 (Box 5)
  - 1937 (spring & summer) Dallas #174 (Box 5)
  - 1940-1 (fall & winter) Minneapolis #181 (Box 6)
  - 1942 (spring & summer) Chicago #184 (Box 6)
  - 1943 (spring & summer) Chicago #186 (Box 7)
  - 1944 (spring & summer) Chicago #188 (Box 7)
  - 1945 (spring & summer) Philadelphia #190 (Box 8)
  - 1946 (spring & summer) Philadelphia #192 (Box 8)
  - 1948 (spring & summer) Philadelphia #196 (Box 9)
  - 1950 (spring & summer) Philadelphia #200 (Box 9)
  - 1950-1 (fall & winter) Philadelphia #201 (Box 10)
  - 1951 (spring & summer) Greensboro, NC (Box 10)
  - 1951 (spring & summer) Philadelphia #202 (Box 10)
  - 1953-4 (fall & winter) Philadelphia #207 (Box 11)
  - 1954 (Christmas) Chicago (Box 11)
  - 1955 (spring & summer) Atlanta #210 (Box 11)
  - 1957 (spring & summer) Philadelphia #214 (Box 12)
  - 1958 (spring & summer) Boston #218 (Box 12)
  - 1959-60 (fall & winter) Philadelphia #219 (Box 13)
  - 1962 (spring & summer) Greensboro, NC 231F (Box 13)
  - 1962 (Christmas) Chicago (Box 13)
  - 1965-6 (fall & winter) Philadelphia #231 (Box 14)
  - 1965-6 (fall & winter) Greensboro #231F (Box 14)
  - 1968 (spring & summer) Atlanta (Box 15)
  - 1968-9 (fall & winter) Greensboro, NC (Box 15)
  - 1971 (spring & summer) Atlanta #242A (Box 16)
  - 1971 (spring & summer) Greensboro, NC #242A (Box 16)
  - 1971-2 (fall & winter) Greensboro, NC #243G (Box 17)
  - 1974 (spring & summer) Eastern edition #248K (Box 17)
  - 1974-5 (fall & winter) Eastern edition (Box 18)
  - 1976-7 (fall & winter) Southern edition #253H (Box 18)
  - 1977 (spring & summer) Southern edition #254A (Box 19)
  - 1980 (spring & summer) Southern edition #260K (Box 19)
  - 1980-1 (fall & winter) Southern edition #261H (Box 20)
  - 1983 (spring & summer) Southern edition #266A (Box 20)
  - 1983-4 (fall & winter) Southern edition #267G (Box 21)
  - 1984 (spring & summer) Catalog of the Future, boxed edition (Box 21)
  - 1986 (spring & summer) Centennial edition (Box 22)
  - 1988 (spring & summer) “B” catalog (Box 22)
  - 1988 (Annual Home, Hardware, Auto and Leisure) “Y” catalog (Box 22)
  - 1988 (Wishbook) (Box 23)
  - 1991-2 (fall & winter) edition G/F/LY/YV #283 (Box 23)
  - 1992 (Wishbook) edition E/N/AC (Box 23)
  - 1994 (Annual) edition W/R/AL/LH #286 (Box 24)